-嘿 -嘿
Oh, my God, you cleaned! Look at these floors!
天啊，你打掃過了 看看地板
You did the windows! I have been begging you for months! And you did, you cleaned.
你還擦了窗戶 我跟你提了好幾個月，你真的打掃了
-And nagging works! -No, I didn't actually do this.
-嘮叨是有用的 -不，事實上這不是我做的
Oh, no. Was I cleaning in my sleep again?
不 我又邊睡覺邊打掃了？
No, it wasn't you.
不，打掃的人也不是你
-Well, then, who? -I got a maid. Yay!
-那麼是誰？ -我請了一個女傭，耶
I hope by "maid" you mean "mistress" because if some other woman was cleaning..
我希望你說的「女傭」是指「情婦」 因為有其他女人在打掃…
Now, honey, I know you don't like to relinquish control.
甜心，我知道你不喜歡 讓出控制權
"Relinquish" is just a fancy word for "lose."
「讓出」的意思 應該就是「失去」吧
She's nice, and she mentioned that she adored the way you arranged the sponges.
她真的很棒，她還說 她喜歡你放海綿的方式
Did she really say that?
她真的那麼說？
Yes, I distinctly remember because I thought it was a joke.
對，我會記得 因為我以為她在開玩笑
-Now, just give her a chance, okay? -Fine, I can do it.
-給她一個機會，好嗎？ -好吧，我辦得到的
-What's the matter? -Usually when I'm this anxious, I clean.
-怎麼了？ -通常我一焦慮就會打掃
The One With The Stain
本集播出：有污點的那個
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Whose cell phone is that? It's just so annoying. Everywhere you go.
是誰的行動電話在響？ 那真的很吵，走到哪裡都會發生這種事
I think it's coming from your bag.
我想聲音是從你的包包裡傳出來的
I never get calls!
從來沒有人會打電話給我
Hello?
喂
Hi, it's Eric, from the Halloween party. Ursula's fiance.
嗨，我是萬聖節派對上的艾力克 烏蘇拉的未婚夫
Oh, my God, Eric, hi! Wait, how'd you get this number?
天啊，艾力克，嗨 等一下，你怎麼知道我的電話號碼？
I have a friend who's a cop, and he got it for me.
我有個朋友在當警察 他幫我查到的
Wow. What an incredible violation and wonderful surprise!
那真的是太不可思議了 我嚇了一大跳
Listen, I just.. I thought you should know I broke up with Ursula.
我想你應該知道 我跟烏蘇拉分手了
Oh, you did? He did it, he did it!
是嗎？他辦到了
-What did he do? -I'm talking!
-他做了什麼？ -我在講電話
Anyway, I was wondering if you were the sort of person who eats lunch?
總之我很好奇 你會不會吃午餐？
Are you asking me out?
你是在約我嗎？
Because it'd be kind of weird since you just broke up with my sister.
因為那很奇怪 你剛剛才跟我姐姐分手
Yeah, okay. I'm sorry. Bye.
好吧，抱歉，再見
No, no. Wait! I was just saying that so you'd think I was a good person.
不，等一下，我會那麼做 是希望你把我當成好人
Fight for me.
為我奮鬥吧
I won't take "no" for an answer.
我不會接受你的拒絕
Not great, but we can work on it at lunch.
雖然不是很好 但我們能邊吃午餐邊練習
I can be at your apartment in two hours.
我可以在兩個小時裡 趕到你家
Great. How do you know where I live?
太棒了，你怎麼知道我住在哪裡？
I've got friends too.
我也有朋友
Okay, bye.
好吧，再見
Oh, my God, I'm going out with Eric!
天啊，我要跟艾力克約會
This day is really gonna be so much better than I thought it was gonna be.
今天比我想像中還要美好
Oh, Ross, I can't make lunch.
羅斯，我沒辦法跟你吃午餐
So apparently I'm available for lunch.
很明顯地 我午餐時間有空
I can't. I'm busy. I'm apartment hunting.
我沒辦法，我很忙 我在找房子
You're moving?
你要搬家？
I can't live with Joey once the baby comes.
孩子生下來後 我沒辦法跟喬伊一起住
I don't want my child's first words to be, "How you doing?"
我不希望我的孩子會說的第一句話 是「你好嗎？」
So does Joey know you're moving?
喬伊知道你要搬家嗎？
I haven't discussed it with him, but I know he'll be relieved.
我還沒有跟他談 但我知道他會覺得如釋重負
Last week, he brought this girl over, and I talked to her about morning sickness.
上星期他帶一個女孩回家 我跟她談害喜的問題
Then I showed her pictures from my pregnancy book.
還把我懷孕紀念冊的照片 拿給她看
-That's not really porn? -Not so much.
-那不會很煽情嗎？ -一點都沒有
I heard in the elevator this morning that a woman in my building died.
今天早上我在電梯裡聽說 我住的公寓裡有個女住戶過世了
Oh, my God. Was she old? Does she have a view?
天啊，她很老嗎？ 她的公寓景觀好嗎？
I don't know, but how great would that be? You living in my building?
我不知道，但那一定會很棒 你搬到我的公寓裡來
I could take care of the baby, I could come over whenever I want..
我可以照顧寶寶 想過去就過去…
with your permission.
當然得先得到你的允許
That really would be great. Well, can we see it?
那真的很棒 我們能去看看嗎？
Maybe we shouldn't. I mean, if she just died this morning.
或許我們不該那麼做 我是說她今天早上才過世
Yeah. No. No, you're right.
對，不，你說的對
-Shall we? -Yeah.
-可以嗎？ -好吧
Yes?
有什麼事嗎？
Hi. I'm Ross Geller. I live in the building.
嗨，我是羅斯蓋勒 我住在這棟公寓裡
And I'm Rachel, an admirer of the building.
我是瑞秋 我很喜歡這棟公寓
I heard about Mrs. Verhoeven passing away, and I am so sorry for your loss.
聽說佛哈芬太太過世了 我真的很遺憾
-She didn't pass away. -What?
-她沒有過世 -什麼？
-My mother's still alive. -Oh, thank God!
-我媽媽還活著 -謝天謝地
It looked like we were gonna lose her this morning, but she's a tough old bird.
她今天早上差點就過世了 但她是個意志力很強的老太婆
Are you close with her?
你跟她很熟嗎？
Of course. She and I would talk all the time..
當然，我們常常…
in the laundry room.
在洗衣間聊天
You speak Dutch?
你會說荷蘭文？
（荷蘭語）
You know, I would, but it's just too painful.
我會的 但那太痛苦了
So she's really not dead.
她真的沒死
No. She's hanging in there.
不，她還在裡面
Could you tell me, is she hanging in in a one-bedroom or a two?
你能告訴我她住的公寓 是一房還是兩房嗎？
Mrs. Bing, this tile cleaner is incredible. Where did you get it?
賓太太，這個清潔劑太棒了 你在哪裡買的？
Oh, well.. I make it myself.
喔… 那是我自己做的
It's two parts ammonia and one part lemon juice. The secret ingredient is..
兩份的阿摩尼亞加一份的檸檬汁 秘方是…
You know what? We just met.
你知道嗎？我們才剛剛認識
Okay. I'm gonna go get the clothes from the laundry room now.
好吧，我去洗衣間拿衣服
When I come back, I'll clean behind the refrigerator.
我回來後 會打掃冰箱後面
I love her.
我愛她
I'll be back in a minute.
我馬上回來
Okay.
好吧
-See? I told you. -She stole my jeans!
-看吧？我告訴過你 -她偷了我的牛仔褲
What?
什麼？
I've been looking for them all week, and she is wearing them.
我找了一個星期 她正穿著它
So she stole your pants and then came back and wore them in front of you?
她偷了你的褲子，然後回來 在你面前穿著它？
Don't you see? It's the perfect crime!
你不明白嗎？ 這是完美犯罪
She must have been planning this for years!
她一定計劃了好幾年
I'll prove it to you, okay.
我會證明給你看的
I dropped a pen in my lap, and it left an ink stain on the crotch.
我把筆掉在大腿上 在胯部留下了墨水印子
When she comes back, I will find it and show you that stain!
她回來後，我會找到它 讓你看看那個墨水印子
Isn't it possible the company that sold the jeans made more than just the one pair?
賣出那件牛仔褲的公司難道 只做了一件牛仔褲嗎？
I guess.
我猜你說的對
Shouldn't we give her the benefit of the doubt before we snoop around her crotch?
我們應該先找找看 再去看她的胯部吧？
Fine. I'm just glad I didn't give her my secret ingredient.
好吧，我很高興 我沒有告訴她我的秘方
Out of curiosity, what is your secret ingredient?
我真的很好奇 你的秘方是什麼？
Yeah.
對
-Hi. -Come in. I'm so glad you're here.
-嗨 -請進，我很高興你來了
Yeah. Me too.
對，我也是
Not in the shaky, angry way that you are, though.
但不像你 那麼震驚憤怒
Sorry. I just saw Ursula. I had to get the engagement ring back.
抱歉，我剛剛見過烏蘇拉 我得把訂婚戒指拿回來
Just seeing her brought it all back.
看到她讓我想起一切
All the lies, the way she used me.
那些謊言，還有她是怎麼利用我的
I just.. I get so angry, just looking at her..
我只是…光是看到她 我就覺得好生氣…
-Face. -Yeah. Yeah.
-我是說看到她的臉 -對
I'm sorry. It's just, when I look at you..
抱歉 當我看到你…
I see her.
我就像是看到了她
And when I see her, I get a little bit angry.
我看到她時 會覺得很生氣
So where do you wanna eat?
你要去哪裡吃飯？
Not that I'm not enjoying watching you flip out.
我不是不喜歡看著你發瘋
Sorry.
抱歉
-Maybe this is too weird. -Wait.
-或許這太奇怪了 -等一下
There's only a problem when I look at you.
我看著你時 只會有一個問題
I got it. I got it.
我知道了
No, don't tear out your eyes!
不，別把你的眼睛挖出來
-I was just gonna take out my lenses. -Oh, yeah. Try that.
-我只是要把隱形眼鏡拿掉 -好吧，試試看
So is that better?
那樣子好多了嗎？
Not really.
才怪
You're blurry, but you still look like Ursula. You're "Blursula."
你看起來很模糊，還是很像烏蘇拉 你是「模糊的烏蘇拉」
Okay, wait. Maybe..
好吧，等一下，或許…
If I just don't look at you for a while.
或許我該 暫時不要看你
See? It works. I'm not angry at all anymore. This is a great date!
看吧？成功了 我不再生氣，這是個很棒的約會
Yeah, not so much.
對，沒那麼棒啦
It's kind of hard to have a conversation.
那樣子很難說話
Oh, no. Sure, we can have a conversation.
不，當然，我們可以說話
Tell me a little something about yourself.
跟我談談你自己
Oh, me?
我嗎？
Look, Eric, turn around.
聽著，艾力克，轉過來
I like you, but it shouldn't be this hard. This is our first date.
我喜歡你，但它不應該這麼難 這是我們第一次約會
First dates are supposed to be about excitement and electricity and..
第一次約會應該是 刺激，火花四射…
"He just touched my hand, did he mean to?" and first kisses..
「他剛剛摸了我的手 他是有意的嗎？」，還有初吻…
Second kisses.
第二次接吻
Thanks for the coffee, or:
謝謝你的咖啡
（荷蘭語）
Yeah, we're done.
對，我們喝完了
（荷蘭語）
Hey, Ross. You wanna go see that new lMAX movie on tide pools?
羅斯，你要去人工造浪池 看新的立體電影嗎？
-Really? -No.
-真的嗎？ -不
But I got Knicks tickets for you, me and Chandler.
但我幫你，我跟錢德 弄到了尼克隊的門票
Sweet!
太棒了
And then afterwards, we can go to a strip joint.
之後我們可以去脫衣舞酒店
-Really? -No.
-真的嗎？ -不
All right, let's go.
好吧，我們走
I have to stop by my place.
我得先回家一趟
To tape the game? You do this every time. You're not gonna be on TV!
你要錄球賽嗎？你每次都這麼做 你又沒有要上電視
No, I have to see if this apartment became available.
不，我得去看看 那間公寓是不是空下來了
-You're switching apartments? -It's not for me, it's for Rachel.
-你要換公寓？ -不是我，是瑞秋要搬家
-She has an apartment. -When the baby comes, she's gonna move.
-她已經有公寓了 -寶寶一出生她就要搬家
-She is? -Yeah.
-真的嗎？ -對
You didn't expect her to live there with the baby?
你該不會希望她跟寶寶 住在那裡吧？
I didn't really think about it.
我真的沒想過
（荷蘭語）
Hey, Gunther, you're an ezel.
阿甘，你是個混蛋
（荷蘭語）
Damn it!
該死
-Nice jeans. -Oh, thanks.
-你的牛仔褲很漂亮 -謝謝
-I like your top. -Oh. You're not getting it.
-我喜歡你的上衣 -你不會拿到它的
-What happened? -Oh. I fell asleep!
-發生了什麼事？ -我睡著了
I was thinking about taking my lunch break.
我想要午休一下
Will you do the top of the cabinets? That'll work up your appetite for lunch.
你能擦一下櫥櫃上面嗎？ 那會讓你午餐時食慾大增
All right.
好吧
Hello.
哈囉
What's going on?
發生了什麼事？
I'm sorry. I've never had a maid before. Is this not okay?
抱歉，我沒有請過女傭 這樣子不行嗎？
I don't understand.
我不瞭解
Why was your head just between my legs?
為什麼你的頭 會在我的雙腿之間？
That's a fair question.
那是好問題
Well, my head was between your legs..
我的頭 會在你的雙腿之間…
because I find you very attractive.
因為我覺得 你非常迷人
Are you coming onto me?
你喜歡上我了？
Apparently.
沒錯
-Hey. -Hey.
-嘿 -嘿
-How was the game? -It was okay. I ate way too much.
-球賽好玩嗎？ -還不錯，我吃太多了
I was talking to Ross, and he said you were looking for a new place.
我跟羅斯談過 他說你在找新公寓
Yeah. Hopefully across the street. If certain Dutch people would just let go.
對，我希望能搬到對街去 如果那些荷蘭人願意讓出公寓
I was kind of hoping you'd stay.
我希望你留下來
Joey, I have to go. There's no room for a baby here.
喬伊，我得搬走 這裡住不下一個寶寶
No room? It's a baby. It's, like, this big.
住不下？它只是一個寶寶 它就這麼大吧
You could put it over here.
你可以把它放在這裡
Or we could put it right here. It's cute, right?
或是這裡 那很可愛吧？
Or put it over here. You wouldn't even notice it.
或是這裡 你根本不會注意到它的
"Where's the baby?" "Oh, it's right over.."
「寶寶在哪裡？」 「它就在…」
Honey, it's not just a matter of where you put it.
甜心，問題不只是 要把它放在哪裡
A baby changes everything. They cry all the time.
寶寶會改變你全部的生活 它們總是哭個不停
Imagine bringing home some girl and trying to score with a screaming baby.
想像你帶女孩回家 想跟她上床時寶寶卻哭個不停
I could use a challenge. It's getting pretty easy.
我可以接受挑戰 那應該會很容易
It's so sweet that you want me to stay, but I can't.
你要我留下來真的很貼心 但我不能那麼做
It would disrupt your entire life.
那會毀了你的生活
It's just.. I love living with you so much.
那只是… 我很喜歡跟你一起住
-I wish things didn't have to change. -I know.
-我希望一切都不必改變 -我知道
You know, I blame Ross for this.
我真的很怪羅斯
I do too, a little bit.
我也有點怪他
I'm gonna miss you.
我會想念你的
You're the hottest roommate I ever had.
你是我遇過 最辣的室友
Oh, no, I have to go. I have a massage appointment.
不，我得走了 有人預約我去按摩
No, stay here. We'll keep doing this. I'll pay you.
不，留下來，我們繼續吧 我可以付錢給你
No, I've gotten in trouble for that before.
不，之前我因為那麼做 惹上了大麻煩
-I'll see you later? -Absolutely.
-待會見？ -沒問題
I love the way you kiss.
我喜歡你接吻的方式
Really? That's the thing I'm worst at! You'll see.
真的嗎？那是我最遜的地方 你等著瞧吧
Hey.
嘿
-Hey. I think Brenda needs a raise. -How come?
-我想布蘭達需要加薪 -為什麼？
Because I put my head between her legs.
因為我把頭 放在她的雙腿之間
-To see her pants? -They're my pants!
-你要看她的褲子？ -那是我的褲子
Are you sure? Did you see the stain?
你確定嗎？ 你看到墨水印子了？
No. I was getting into position, and then everything went dark.
不，我才剛剛就定位 後來就眼前一陣黑
She is not stealing from us, okay. Will you let this go?
她沒有偷我們的東西 你能不能算了？
Fine.
好吧
-She's wearing my bra! -Oh, dear God!
-她穿著我的胸罩 -天啊
My pink, flowered bra! I recognize the strap!
我的粉紅色小花胸罩 我認得那條肩帶
Yet you don't recognize that you're crazy?
你不知道自己瘋了嗎？
Here's the plan. I'm going to leave, and you're gonna look at Brenda's bra.
我有個計劃，我先離開 你得去看布蘭達的胸罩
Here's another plan. No.
我也有個計劃，不行
I would do it, but she thinks I'm attracted to her.
我很想這麼做 但她以為我被她吸引
-Why? -Did you not hear where my head was?
-為什麼？ -你不知道剛剛我的頭放在哪裡嗎？
We're a team. We're in this together.
我們是一國的 這件事我們都有份
I fear a jury will see it the same way.
我擔心陪審團 也會那麼認為
Do this for me. I catch you looking at women's breasts all the time.
為我這麼做 我常抓到你在瞄女人胸部
You see that?
你看到了？
Do you see this?
你看到這個了嗎？
All right, yes. Okay. I get your point.
好吧，我瞭解你的意思
But if it's not her bra, will you just let the woman clean?
如果那是她的胸罩 你能讓她打掃嗎？
Yes. You'll know it's mine because on the right cup, there's a very noticeable rip.
對，你會知道它是我的 因為罩杯對了，胸罩還破了一個大洞
You need new clothes.
你需要新衣服
-Hi. How is she? -It's not looking good.
-她還好嗎？ -情況看起來不妙
Well, I brought her some bloemen.
我幫她帶了一些花過來
That's so sweet. Would you like to say goodbye? It would mean a lot to her.
那真的是太棒了，你要跟她道別嗎？ 那對她來說一定很重要
Oh, I don't know that it would.
我不知道該不該這麼做
-Well, her memory is pretty much gone. -All right, then.
-她幾乎不記得任何人了 -那麼好吧
-Hey! -Welcome back.
-嘿 -歡迎你回來
-Shall we pick up from where we left off? -I'm still tired from this afternoon.
-我們要繼續嗎？ -我還因為今天下午的事覺得很累
-Why? -The sex.
-為什麼？ -我們做愛了
-What sex? -Our sex.
-什麼？ -你跟我做愛了
We didn't have sex.
我們沒有做愛
If I didn't have sex with you, I had sex with somebody that looked like..
如果我沒有跟你做愛 我一定是跟一個長得很像…
-You had sex with Ursula? -A little bit.
-你跟烏蘇拉做愛？ -有一點啦
She walked in, I thought she was you and I kissed her and..
她走進來，我以為她是你 我吻了她…
-You didn't notice different clothes? -I was just so excited to see you.
-你沒注意到衣服不一樣嗎？ -我看到你覺得很興奮
-This is too weird. -No, it's not. I don't wanna lose you.
-這真的是太奇怪了 -不會的，我不想失去你
It's like I was saying to Ursula when I was making love..
我在做愛的時候 跟烏蘇拉說…
Yeah. It's too weird.
對，那太奇怪了
So I guess this is it.
我猜就這麼吧
Yeah.
對
Maybe it's for the best.
或許這麼做是最好的
-You smell just like her. -Yeah, so do you.
-你的味道跟她一樣 -對，你也是
-What are you doing? -I'm leaning.
-你在做什麼？ -我在彎腰
This is where I lean.
我都在這裡彎腰
Okay.
好吧
-Brenda, a bee! -What?
-布蘭達，有蜜蜂 -什麼？
It's flown into your blouse, and you better undo your buttons lest it sting you.
它飛進你的上衣裡了 你最好快解開釦子免得被蟄傷
-I think I know what's going on here. -You do?
-我想我知道這是怎麼一回事了 -是嗎？
Look, I know it must be hard that your wife is a lesbian..
我知道你一定很難受 你太太是女同志…
but it's wrong. You're married.
但這是不對的，你結婚了
-I totally understand. -Okay, good.
-我完全瞭解 -太好了
Could I just see your bra?
我能看看你的胸罩嗎？
Hi.
嗨
-Where'd you get those jeans? -You gave them to me.
-你怎麼會有那條牛仔褲？ -是你送我的
-No, I didn't! -All right, I took them.
-我才沒有 -好吧，我拿走它
I figured it'd be okay because you've got a big ink stain on the crotch.
我以為你不會介意 因為它在胯部的地方有一大塊墨水印子
-Oh, no! Did you take my bra too? -What bra?
-不，你也拿走了我的胸罩嗎？ -什麼胸罩？
-The pink one with the flowers. -You mean the one you're wearing?
-有小花的粉紅色胸罩 -你是說你正在穿的這件胸罩嗎？
I quit!
我不幹了
Sounds about right.
正是時候
What is this?
這是什麼？
This is just to give you an idea.
我只希望你考慮一下
We can put screens here so that the baby has privacy..
我們可以在這裡裝拉鏈 寶寶還是有隱私…
and maybe a mobile over the crib..
在搖籃上面裝個音樂鈴
and here's a baby monitor which, till the baby comes, we can use as walkie-talkies.
這是寶寶監控器 寶寶沒出生前，我們可以把它當對講機
You're so sweet!
你真的是太體貼了
Oh, my God! And you gave the baby Hugsy!
天啊 你幫寶寶買了企鵝寶寶
That's really just to show where the baby would go.
我只是要向你示範 寶寶該躺在哪裡
Why don't I hold on to him so there's no confusion.
快把它交給我吧 免得你誤會了
Joey, the baby is gonna be crying. It's gonna be loud.
喬伊，寶寶會哭的 那會非常地吵
-I'm loud. -It's gonna be up all night.
-我很吵 -他會整晚不睡
-I'm up all night. -It's gonna poop.
-我也會 -他會大便
Hello!
哈囉
What about all the women?
你的女朋友們呢？
If I'm bringing home a woman who can't stand a baby..
如果我把一個 受不了寶寶的女人帶回家…
then maybe I don't wanna be with that woman.
或許我根本 不該跟那個女人在一起
Or maybe we'll do it in the bathroom of the club!
或許我們該在 俱樂部的浴室裡做愛
But I won't say stuff like that around the baby.
但我不會在寶寶面前 那麼說
Joey, are you sure?
喬伊，你確定嗎？
Yeah. Look, I know sometimes it'll be hard, okay..
對，聽著，我知道 有時候會很辛苦…
but it'll also be really, really great.
但它也會非常棒
Please, Rachel, I really want you to stay.
拜託，瑞秋 我真的希望你留下來
I want me to stay too. Thank you.
我也想留下來，謝謝你
-Joey, look at this crib. It's so cute. -I know. I found it on the street.
-喬伊，看看這個搖籃，它好可愛 -我知道，我在街上撿到它
Are you..? Really? This is in such good condition.
你是…真的嗎？ 它看起來還不錯
Whoa! What's under the cover?
被子下面是什麼？
-I don't know. -It's moving.
-我不知道 -他在動
It's got a tail! Get it out of here!
他有尾巴，快把它搬出去
Okay!
好吧
（謹以本片獻給 珍珠哈蒙）
Well, the old lady died. And how do I know?
那位老太太過世了 我怎麼會知道呢？
Because her dying wish was for one last kiss.
因為她的遺願是 給她最後一吻
And because I'm such a strong, strapping alleenstaande..
因為我是個強壯的大男人…
I had to carry her body to the lobby.
我得把她的屍體抱到大廳
You know, and she was not a slight woman.
而且她真的 一點都不瘦
But I don't care, because you got the apartment. Yes!
但我不在乎 因為你拿到那間公寓了，太棒了
Yeah. I think I'm gonna stay here.
對，我想我要留在這裡
Isn't that great?
那真的很棒吧？
What..? You.. But.. Bu..
什麼？你… 但是…
（荷蘭語）